<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Satya Tanwar - On Tech And Life</title><link>https://blog.satyatanwar.com/</link><description>Recent content on Satya Tanwar - On Tech And Life</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 06:15:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.satyatanwar.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scripting kubernetes-the-hard-way</title><link>https://blog.satyatanwar.com/posts/technology/scripting-kubernetes-the-hard-way/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 06:15:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.satyatanwar.com/posts/technology/scripting-kubernetes-the-hard-way/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="the-challenge">The Challenge&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>During preparation for my &lt;strong>Certified Kubernetes Administrator&lt;/strong> (CKAD) and &lt;strong>Certified Kubernetes Security Specialist&lt;/strong> (CKS) exams I realized the value of having a local Kubernetes cluster that can be used to experiment. Initially, I followed the instructions from &lt;a href="https://github.com/kelseyhightower/kubernetes-the-hard-way">kubernetes-the-hard-way&lt;/a> by &lt;strong>Kelsey Hightower&lt;/strong> and manually built a local cluster on my Windows 10 laptop. It was a great starting point to experiment, but I faced many challenges with the manual installation. While experimenting much of my time was getting wasted in either identifying the changes that made the cluster unusable or in rebuilding the cluster again when not able to find the root cause of failure. This made me realize that I need an automated and repeatable solution to build a local cluster. As the process may allow me to focus on experimenting with various Kubernetes concepts instead of fixing or building clusters if some issue occurs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Beginning</title><link>https://blog.satyatanwar.com/posts/the-beginning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 06:15:36 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.satyatanwar.com/posts/the-beginning/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have debated with myself for a long time before committing to sharing my tech and life experience. I always felt that there are thousands of blogs, and the world doesn&amp;rsquo;t need one more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>https://blog.satyatanwar.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.satyatanwar.com/about/</guid><description>Welcome!! 🤓 I&amp;rsquo;m Satya Tanwar, author of this blog.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently a Lead Cloud Architect with Humana Inc. I&amp;rsquo;ve held many different roles in IT, including Solution Architect, Technical Architect, and Integration Consultant. For updated information, please see my LinkedIn profile.
In addition to my professional experience, I hold Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree(2014) in Information Technology and a Master&amp;rsquo;s degree(2016) in Healthcare Informatics. I live with my wife and 5-year-old son in Massachusetts.</description></item></channel></rss>